MICAH BOTTOMS

CONTACT INFORMATION

Cell phone 318.364.0466 Email bottoms.micah.3@gmail.com

PERSONAL REFERENCES

DR. KYLE PIERCE

Professor of Kinesiology, Olympic Weightlifting Coach 318.344.1561

BRANDON BOOTH

Former Mentor 314.973.7294

TIMOTHY WINTER

Kinesiology Department Chair 318.797.5107 timothy.winter@lsus.edu

CAREER FOCUS

I love exercise and athletics, both as a participant and a student. I am very passionate about helping others optimize their training based on their goals. My education has prepared me to do so and I am excited to gain experience and positively impact others.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

SPORTS PERFORMANCE COACH

Sterling's Team Speed | November 2021-current

Strength, Agility and Speed Training for Young Athletes Reference: Matt Remaley, Head Coach 303.842.4054

MANAGER, TRAINER

Anytime Fitness Southern Loop | December 2020-November 2021

Strength Training, Marketing, Cleaning, etc. Reference: Jerry Lorey, Owner 318.525.7902

BOYS ASSISTANT SOCCER COACH

North Desoto High School | May 2017 - May 2019

Coached technical and tactical, as well as strength and plyometric training
Lead team to playoff appearances both seasons

Reference: Head Coach Aaron Barnes 318.218.1527

PHSYICAL THERAPY TECHNICIAN

Desoto Physical Therapy | July-November 2017

Facilitated PT for multiple types of rehabilitation Gained valuable experience which focused professional direction Reference: Doug James 318.775.9870

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT/ VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

- -Worldview Academy Leadership Camps: Summer 2018 & 2019
- -Summer Grove Baptist Church Compassion House: Spring 2019
- -Canon City Pregnancy Center: Spring 2020
- -Evangelical Free Church AWANA Program: Academic year 2019-20
- -GOLA coffee shop: Spring 2019
- -Worldview at the Abbey gap year program: Academic year 2019-20, 2020-21
- -Desoto Parish Volunteer Firefighter Dept.: 2013-2014

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMMUNITY HEALTH-STRENGTH AND CONDITIONING

Louisiana State University Shreveport | 2017 - 2020 GPA 3.35

Dean's List S 17-18, F 18-19, S 18-19 Studied under Dr. Kyle Pierce

SKILLS, ABILITIES AND CHARACTERISTICS

- -Passion for research
- -Strong desire to learn and grow
- -Appreciation for constructive criticism
- -Experienced at working with children
- -Love for teaching
- -Emphasis on strength in diversity